Peter Safwat

Software Engineer

 Birth
 March 23, 1998

 Address
 Imbaba, Giza

 Phone
 0120 6284 377

Mail p.pator@outlook.com Github github.com/peter44322 LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/peterzacch

SUMMARY

I'm +3 years expriance Software Engineer, i start coding when i was 13, programming is more than a job for me it is a hoppy. i'm a self-motivated ,creative ,problem solver and determined Engineer. my objective is to contribute more to the open source community.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

2018-present

Bee Interactives., Full-time

- Developing and directing software system validation and testing methods.
- Analyzing data to effectively coordinate the installation of new systems or the modification of existing systems.
- Managing the software development lifecycle.
- Developing and executing project plans.
- Applying mathematics and statistics to problem-solving initiatives.
- Applying best practices and standard operating procedures.

Backend Developer

2017-2018

Egyadv., Full-time

- Main focus on coding and debugging
- Build high-quality reusable code that can be used in thew future
- Develop functional and sustainable web applications with clean codes
- Define and communicate technical and design requirements
- Collaborate with Front-end developers

Programming Instructor

2017-2018

Pharaonic Technology Systems., Part-time

- Provide hands-on instruction and practical training in Java, Python, and Arduino.
- Teach courses from beginning level to advance.
- Create instructional materials

EDUCATION

BCS. Faculty of computer and artificial intelligence

2016-2020

Cairo University

Major - Computer science

Minor - Information systems

SKILLS

Languages Arabic (mother tongue)

English (professional)

Programming

Languages

PYTHON, JAVASCRIPT, C#, C++, PHP, JAVA

Databases MySql, postgresql, mongodb, Redis

Frameworks Laravel, Reactjs, Angular, Django, express, Ruby on Rails

PROJECTS

World Youth Forum

A System that helped the WYF organizers filter and validate all the candidates for the Forum, with a very large database operation we overcome many performance challenges

Orange sonetelhaya

A Video Generator, I Worked in this project as a full-stack,

- creating the frontend using react
- in order to preview the video in a short time we used Lottie.js.
- and we recorded the video using node.js, puppeteer and FFmpeg.
- we used WebSockets to give realtime feedback to the user.

Dijkstra Visualization

An Interactive Dijkstra Algorithm Visualization tool using react and vis.js. visualize the solution of max flow problem and shorts pathh

Picks courier

descriptionPicks courier is a start-up based in Cairo, Egypt. it offers delivery solutions to individuals, SMEs, and corporates. We own and manage a highly professional courier network through an innovative business model.

Game Ai

An Ai For a searching game it uses prolog to make tree of game states. it also has an interactive ui for setting the intial state of the game and show the solution.

C Lexical Analyzer

Python Lexical Analyzer for c syntax. it uses the magic of regex to edintify the syntax and cateogrize them.

Music Player

Web Music Player Using nextjs and napster Apis.

KingsMen

An Express.js Cloths shop Web app with mongodb database

Vector quantization

Java Impelmentation for the Vector quantization Compress Algorithm.

Fuzzy ToolBox

Fuzzy Logic Impelmentation in Python with a graph plotter

Adaptive huffman coding

Java Impelmentation for Adaptive huffman Compression Algorithm.

smooth curve fitting

Python genetic Algorithm used to fit a curve giving some points and graph them.

Knapsack genetic algorithm

Solving the Knapsack problem using genatic algorithm.

Tic tac toe Game

Reactjs Tic Tac Toe Game

Calculating pi by collisions

A Visualization for calculating the digits of pi using elastic collisions between two objects of different masses and a wall. Let me explain with this diagram.

CryptoMail

Secure nodejs Mail server implemented using blockchanin with peer to peer archticture.

OPEN SOURCE PACKAGES

DyForm

An Open source Laravel package to help create dynamic forms with high-performance insert and retrieve operations.

Completeness Checker

An Open source Laravel package to help track the completeness of an entity, it calculate how many fields the user has filled and it generates a percentage of completeness.

Swaggerator

An Open source Laravel package to help Developers document their APIS With a bunch of easy commands.

JoQueryGenerator

An open source laravel package to help obtomizing datatables query, with the help of the colvis addon it joins table conditionaly.

Html Extractor

Nodejs tool for extracting html ,js ,css files from a giving url

Vast Converter

Converter for converting vast xml files version 1 to vast version 2

BOOKS & COURSES

Books Clean Code - Robert Cecil Martin

The Nature of Code - Daniel Shiffman

Head First Design Patterns - Elisabeth Freeman and Kathy Sierra

Courses CS50's Introduction to Computer Science - Harvard

Good Parts of JavaScript and the Web - Douglas Crockford

THE ODIN PROJECT
Web Development - Udacity

PUBLICATION

• Laravel dynamic databases - Medium Article

LIFE PHILOSOPHY

however difficult life may seem, there is always something you can do, and succeed at. It matters that you don't just give up - Stephen Hawking

REFERENCES

Available upon request